# **Thomas Nattrass**

RG40

<u>Mobile</u>: 07786485608 <u>Email</u>: <u>tom.n@live.com</u> LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tom-nattrass-0635a142/

#### **Personal Profile**

I thrive on fixing problems and helping other people in the workplace, especially when it helps to complete my own work at the same time. I particularly enjoy adapting to different situations where a solution to the problem may not be so obvious at first. I have taken an interest in many different areas of work and most recently worked as a Support Engineer at Microsoft, having previously qualified as a tax professional via HMRC.

I have completed and received accreditation for studies in both Tax and IT, demonstrating my ability to learn as part of my employment and gain the knowledge required to excel in any role I undertake.

## Skills

I have a variety of that would be useful in the workplace:

- Substantial experience in dealing with customers and colleagues at prominent levels of organisations.
- Professional writing style and an extensive vocabulary, alongside exceptionally good numeracy skills
- Adept problem solver, able to analyse complex issues and provide solutions where applicable.
- Strong communicator and keen to contribute.
- Sociable but professional attitude towards work.
- Confident on the telephone with both colleagues and customers.
- Technology: Windows (Server & Client), Active Directory, Azure, Intune, Endpoint, Exchange, Office 365, WebView2, Firewalls, Adobe Acrobat.

#### **Work Experience**

#### September 2021 – June 2023 – Microsoft:

Having left HMRC to pursue a new career, I was employed by Microsoft as a Support Engineer in the Browser team. I was tasked with managing a wide range of customers based all over the world, at various levels of their organisations all the way up to executive levels. I was responsible for building relationships with the customer and then helping to troubleshoot complex issues stemming from both our technologies and theirs.

My work included, but was not limited to:

- Collecting, analysing, and interpreting logs to identify issues and propose solutions.
  - This included collecting and analysing Memory Dumps, Network Traces (Net Export, Fiddler, Internet Client) and Process Monitor logs.
- Troubleshooting software compatibility issues across various platforms and devices.

- Helping customers to migrate from outdated software and methods to help modernise their environments.
- Working alongside our product group to generate custom solutions for our clients' problems.
- Managing difficult customer conversations when their issues were unable to be resolved.
- Keeping up to date records on a ticketing system, with concise notes that allowed my colleagues and managers to understand the status of a request and its next actions.

During this time, I maintained and exemplary customer service score of 4.85/5 over an 18-month period, often receiving 'customer hero' awards as recognition.

I worked with a wide range of different technologies due to the overlap of the browser with almost every other area of IT. As such, it was important for me to be able to quickly research, understand and then action upon my findings, collaborating with other teams when necessary.

### August 2015 to September 2021 - HMRC:

I began my career in HMRC as part of the Large Business department. This role included carrying out detailed risk reports, providing support for computations and participating in a number of high-profile meetings with directors of multi-national companies. This period helped me to develop my team working skills as well as how to deal with demanding customers who are not necessarily the most cooperative.

At the midpoint of my training, I took the decision to become a caseworker for intermediate size business. As I personally own the cases I worked upon and oversaw, this position allowed me to develop my organisational skills as well as my ability to make decisions and communicate clearly with customers. Following completion of my training course, I continued this role as a caseworker and managed a vast number of cases at any one time, each concerning a different legal or accounting argument.

As part of this role, I completed the HMRC Grade 7 training course. This included an additional degree and covered a wide range of different finance areas such as Accounting, Tax, and related financial law.

I also held position as a digital ambassador and created a corporation tax calculator. This involved learning to code in PowerApps, but I was able to teach myself the required skills and the calculator was published to the entire department shortly after my departure.

## February 2012 to July 2015 – Second Line IT Support, Frimley Park Hospital, Frimley

I was offered a position at Frimley Park as part of the IT qualification I was studying and following this was signed up as a contractor for my breaks from university. This job taught me a great deal about providing support to users who were not technically minded, requiring me to often provide information in basic terms that anyone can understand.

Whilst working here I fulfilled a variety of different roles; I began by manning telephones on the service desk but swiftly moved into second line support and fixing physical problems throughout the Hospital which could not be done remotely. The position has taught me a lot about stepping back and assessing a situation before making any decision as well as how to communicate with different people depending on

the circumstances you are in.

## **Education & Training**

AZ-900 Azure Fundamentals Certified CompTIA A+ Certified

Tax Specialist Programme (CT) (HMRC)

<u>Promotion to Civil Service Grade 7</u> Tax Professional Studies Degree (BA) – 2.1

**Bournemouth University (2012-2015)** 

Accounting and Finance (BA) - 2.1 Finance & Law FDA – Distinction

Farnborough Sixth Form College (2010) – A Levels

During college I achieved A Levels in Maths, Accounting, Law, and Computing.

The Forest School (2008) - GCSEs

At secondary school I achieved 10.5 passes including an A\* in Mathematics.